[Music]
here's an isosceles right triangle with
legs of length 1 so that the hypotenuse
has a length square root of 2. if we
walk from the upper corner to the lower
corner going one unit East and then one
unit South we travel a total of two
units but we can keep poking in the
corners of these paths so that we walk
east south east south east south all the
way down the diagonal to the corner if
we do this process indefinitely have we
produced a proof that the square root of
2 which is the length of the hypotenuse
is exactly the same as 2 which is the
length of the path that we walk how
could this be let's take a zoom in and
see what's going on
foreign
so no this isn't a visual proof that
square root of 2 equals 2. but can you
explain what's going on
if you want to see some honest visual
proofs of some real facts then go check
out my channel